JOHN SOLLY

Medford, Oregon|solly@pm.me

Full-stack developer with domain expertise in GIS, Remote Sensing, and business intelligence. Highlights include TDD web development in Django (Python) and React (TypeScript), in-depth knowledge of CI-CD tooling, and real-world experience on a dev team.

Technologies and Tooling

Python | TypeScript | TDD | Django | React | Node | Pandas | Selenium | Leaflet.js | OpenLayers | GDAL-OGR | Arcpy | Shell | Jenkins | Apache/Nginx | Docker | Git/Jira | Testrail | PostGIS | MongoDB | Arcade

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

YellowfinBl Boise, ID

INTEGRATION CONSULTANT

May 2021 to February 2022

Empower developers as a trusted advisor. Offer technical leadership and ownership in post-sales consulting engagements with tier-1 customers, ensuring a successful customer experience.

- Design, develop and integrate innovative data solutions according to stakeholder requirements.
- Aid in complex deployments and act as an escalation point for L3 support tickets.
- Thought leader on best practices in solution and integration development. Prove processes and patterns to be leveraged by Yellowfin consultants, customers, and partners.

ENVIRONMENTAL SYSTEMS RESEARCH INSTITUTE (Esri)

Redlands, CA

PRODUCT ENGINEER (II)

May 2017 to May 2021

Supported Esri's ArcGIS Dashboards through automated and manual end-to-end functional, performance, and regression QA testing. Release manager, and delegating tasks to internal and external QA resources.

- Create automated regression testing harness for JavaScript based web application. Authored critical sanity and certification test plans run by other internal employees.
- Manage and delegate manual testing tasks to a QA team of four engineers to deliver working software on time with no production bug fixes over three years.
- Define I18N (internationalization) and security test strategy for offshore L10N/I18N testing vendors. Reduced manual testing expenditures from 240 to 100 hours per quarterly release.

CENTER FOR LOCATION SCIENCE | RESEARCH AND TEACHING ASSISTANT

Sept 2015 to May 2017

U.C.S.B COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING | TIER I HELP DESK

Oct 2014 to Jun 2015

PROJECTS

- Blogthedata.com (2021 Present) Author blogsite using a Django (Python) backend. Pure HTML/CSS + bootstrap front end. All code tested, linted, committed, deployed to a Linode cloud server with Github Actions. A PostGIS server powers webmaps built on Leaflet.js.
- **UI Automation of ArcGIS Dashboards (2021)** Create UI functional tests using Python and Selenium. Test harness scheduled through a containerized Jenkins deployment. Test results reported to multiple sources, inducing email, defect tracking tool, and MS Teams Channel. Tests uncovered over 10 high priority defects within a 6-month period.

EDUCATION

OPEN SOURCE SOCIETY UNIVERSITY (OSSU)

github.com/ossu/computer-science Jan 2021 - Present

COMPUTER SCIENCE (Bachelors Equivalent)

Fairfax, VA

May 2017

GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY, GPA 3.93M.S. GEOINFORMATICS AND GEOSPATIAL INTELLIGENCE

Santa Barbara, CA May 2015

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, SANTA BARBARA, GPA 3.85

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, SANTA BARBARA, GPA 3.85 B.A. GEOGRAPHY (GIS & REMOTE SENSING EMPHASIS)